CJ WILLIAMS

PRODUCT DESIGNER, MARKETER, FRONT-END DEVELOPER



Phone

406.579.1985



Email

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



Portfolio

hirecj.com

SOCIAL



LinkedIn

/cjwilliamsworks



GitHub

/silencekillsdesign



Codepen

/silencekillsdesign

EDUCATION

Treehouse Academy

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com
2014 - 2022

Montana State University

Graphic Design & Music Technology Bozeman, MT 2003 - 2008

SKILLS

- UX / UI / IA DESIGN
- HTML / CSS / JS / VUE / NUXT
- ADOBE CC & FIGMA
- MANAGEMENT & LEADERSHIP
- SEMRUSH / HUBSPOT
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- E-COMMERCE MANAGEMENT
- PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CERTIFICATIONS

- GOOGLE UX DESIGN
- GOOGLE DIGITAL MARKETING
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- CERTIFIED NUXT MASTER
- HUBSPOT INBOUND

PROFILE

Hi! I'm CJ, a Product Designer, Front-End Web Developer, and E-Commerce Director, with over 10 years of management experience. I am a strong and compassionate leader with a multi-disciplinary background, able to work and effectively communicate across teams fluidly. I'm a data-informed and logical decision maker always striving to be better. I'm excited to join a team with shared goals, values, and ethics so we can make awesome things together.

EXPERIENCE

Greenridge (Formerly Greenridge Farm)

Director of E-Commerce & Customer Experience / Dec 2022 - Present

- Developed design systems, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes in Figma
- Managed web migration, including DNS, CDN, SFTP, SMTP, API integration
- Led creative design on new brand identity, packaging, and digital spaces
- Optimized organization-wide operations in product development and design
- Strategically improved organic and technical SEO, increasing web traffic over 180%
- Led product development strategy to increase year-over-year online sales by 400%

Hoists.com (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES) Director of E-Commerce & Customer Experience / 2021 - 2023

- Designed Information Architecture for over 2500 product SKU configurations
- Managed Development and Product Design across all company entities
- Managed Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy, budgets, and reporting
- $\bullet \ \ {\it Created infrastructure for Development, Product Design, Sales Support staff}$
- Managed growth of department, creating 5 new roles within the company
 Launched to a reach of over 50k unique visitors in our first year, with paid
- Launched to a reach of over 50k unique visitors in our first year, with paid traffic netting 36k clicks, 1.8M impressions on a \$2k/mo. budget, while generating \$750k in sales in our first year, amidst major supply chain issues

SilenceKillsDesign

Agency Owner - Product Design, Front-End Development, Marketing / 2007 - 2020

- UX Research, Prototyping, Architecture, Testing and Design, primarily for B2B
- Designed responsive admin and end-user UX/UI for data validation and address verification SaaS web apps in higher-ed and finance spaces
- Created, managed, and empowered of multiple brands' presence and identity
- Maintained and managed hosting, server setup and cyber security for clients
- · Architected, designed, and developed B2B and B2C websites and e-commerce
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting

Xtant Medical (Formerly Bacterin International)

Manager of UX and Digital Marketing / 2012 - 2016

- · Led UX Design, architecture, and ongoing development of public-facing site
- Designed and developed investor portals and internal sales portal
- Managed all SEO, SEM, PPC, SMM, Ad Purchasing
- · Led creative Brand design, product design, and growth marketing for rebrand